ray-ban.com 2017-06-07

# Ray-Ban.com Privacy Policy | Ray-Ban US Online Store

This website is managed by a subsidiary of Luxottica Group S.p.A. ("Luxottica"), and the privacy and security measures applicable to this website are designed with the strictest security in mind, so any personal information that you provide via this website is used only for the purposes outlined herein. This privacy policy tells you how Luxottica and its subsidiaries collect and use your personal information, who they share it with and how you can access, change and remove your information. When used in this policy, depending on the context, "we," "our" and "us" refers to Luxottica and its affiliates, individually and collectively.

## HOW WE COLLECT THE INFORMATION

There are many ways that we obtain information from you, including but not limited to: (1) via signup on any of our website(s); (2) from an online, email, retail, fax or telephone purchase; (3) from navigational information about where visitors go on our website; (4) from your use of Ray-Ban’s virtual program; (5) when you enter a Ray-Ban sweepstakes/giveaway; (6) anytime you submit a business reply, product, or warranty card; (7) upon contacting customer care to request Ray-Ban communications; and (8) upon signing up at an event.

## THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

When you register online to receive our product information, you will need to provide us with your name, address and e-mail address. When you make a purchase through Ray-Ban's website, you also will need to give us your telephone number and credit card number so we can process your payment and contact you in the event of any problems with delivery. If you contact our customer care department, you may need to provide us with additional information so that we can respond to your questions or concerns as completely and thoroughly as possible.

In order to provide users and subscribers with the most efficient and enhanced service and to better understand your preferences, we may request your gender, year of birth, sports of interest, shopping preference and product interest. Whether or not you provide this information is entirely up to you. Ray-Ban’s virtual program is completely voluntary. If you use Ray-Ban’s virtual program, we will collect and maintain a copy of the image or images.

We also may collect additional non-personally identifiable information (for example, browser version, IP address) which will provide information regarding the general use of our website. The navigational information allows us to see which areas of our website are most visited and helps us improve the quality of your online experience by recognizing and delivering more of the most desired features and services.

## HOW WE USE THE INFORMATION

This website is generally directed to individuals residing in the United States. As such, all personal information that we obtain about you will be recorded, used and protected by us in accordance with current United States data protection legislation and this privacy policy. To the extent your personal information is recorded or used by our affiliates in Europe it is also covered by European Union data protection legislation and any other applicable laws. By providing us with your personal information, you consent to us processing this personal information in one or more of the ways described in this privacy policy.

We will primarily use your personal information to provide products and services to you, for example:

1\. To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature and to provide you with the relevant products or services (for instance to deliver a prize you may have won in a contest).

2\. To send you information/materials via e-mail or mail about products, offers and news we think could interest you. This information may relate to products, offers and news of Ray-Ban products or any of our other products and services.

3\. To analyze visits to the website and learn about the interests of our visitors as well as visitor’s physical features in the aggregate so we can improve our products and services and deliver the best user experience.

The information obtained during an online purchase is utilized to improve your web experience by enabling you to obtain a faster checkout for purchases and/or opt-in to receive e-mails, which provide you with the latest and greatest information regarding Ray-Ban products and our other products and services.

The information obtained during an online purchase is used only to complete the order online, to confirm the order and shipment of the order via email. You may, upon placement of an order, opt to allow us to save the information for a speedier checkout process the next time. Your payment information is then stored only for the purposes of faster checkout and is not used for any other purpose.

## COOKIES

A cookie is a small removable data file that is stored by your web browser on your computer. Cookies are only used by us to allow you to use the website in the most efficient manner. Cookies allow you to place an order on our website and allow us to enhance and personalize your online surfing and shopping experience. For example, we use cookies to:

1\. Remember the items in your shopping basket

2\. Recognize you when you return to our website

3\. Assist you in efficiently accessing any pictures taken with the virtual program

4\. Analyze visitor behavior

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser settings. Please note, however, that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our website.

We also work with other companies who use tracking technologies, including web beacons, to serve ads on our behalf across the internet. These companies may collect non-personally identifiable information about your visit to our website about your interaction with our communications, including advertising and e-mails. If you object to web beacons, we recommend that you follow the instructions for deleting existing cookies and disabling future cookies. We will still know how many of our e-mails are opened and we will automatically receive your IP address, a unique identifier for your computer or other access device but we will not identify you as an individual.

## SHARING INFORMATION WITH THIRD PARTIES

Luxottica is made up of many companies all over the world, and different companies have different operations and responsibilities within the larger group. Based on those operations and responsibilities we will share your information with our affiliated companies, who will use that information only in the manner set forth in this policy.

We also engage third parties to perform services in connection with the operation of our business. Examples of these services include payment processing and authorization, fraud protection and credit risk reduction, product customization, order fulfillment and shipping, marketing and promotional material distribution, website evaluation, data analysis and, where applicable, data cleansing. We may need to share personal information with these third parties so that they can perform these services, however, we limit the personal information that we give to them and authorize them to use this information only for the purpose of performing those services.

In proceeding with your online order, you agree that both your name and address and those of the delivery name and address (if different) will be checked using third parties such as credit agencies. If you are providing a delivery name and address which is not your own you must have that person's permission to give us their personal information and for us to use it for the purposes specified. By providing it you are saying you have their permission.

We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our agents, including agencies or third party vendors so that they can provide marketing analysis and consult on advertising strategies. This information does not identify individual users. We also may share non-personal information, such as the number of users who visited the website during a specific time period or who purchased a specific product through the website, with our marketing partners, advertisers and others from time to time. This information generally is shared in an aggregated form.

We may release personal information if we believe in good faith that: the law or legal process requires it; if we have been advised by counsel; we have received a valid administrative request from a law enforcement agency; or such release is necessary to protect the rights, property or safety of Luxottica, or any of our respective affiliates, business partners, customers or others.

As with any business, it is possible that as our business develops, we might go through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, sale of all or a portion of our assets or buying online stores or other assets. In such transactions, your information will likely be transferred. You will be notified via a prominent notice on our site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information. You will be deemed to have consented to the transfer of your personally identifiable information to any such successor entity unless you notify us via email to the contrary within the 30 day period.

Personal information submitted to or collected through this website may be stored and/or processed in the United States, United Kingdom, Italy or Canada for the purposes described in this privacy policy. By providing us with your information (including simply using our website), you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country.

We do not share, sell or rent to other third parties any personal information that you provide to us, except with your consent or as described in this Privacy Policy.

## E-MAIL

Our company policy is to not flood people with e-mail correspondence, but simply to give you periodic information so you can stay up to date on what we are offering.

You can easily unsubscribe at any time you want by calling our customer care department at (866) 4RAYBAN (866-472-9226) or by following the instructions contained in the e-mail. It takes some time to put opt outs in effect so you may still receive emails from Ray-Ban for several weeks after your request is received.

We also use your e-mail address to confirm your order and to confirm shipment of your order and to respond to any inquiries you make online. All e-mails you receive will provide you with information as to how to get off the e-mail mailing list if you so desire.

## DIRECT MAIL

If you would like to update your mailing information or want your name and address removed from Ray-Ban's direct mailing list you can give us a call at (866) 4RAYBAN (866-472-9226).

## CHILDREN'S PRIVACY

If you are under 14, you should surf ray-ban.com only with involvement of a parent or guardian. Although we do not specifically direct our website, catalogs or e-mails to children, we strive to provide children with as much customer care as possible without violating their privacy rights. For their protection, we ask that anyone under 14 years of age not attempt to register with Ray-Ban.com or otherwise provide us with any personal information without the consent of a parent or legal guardian.

## ACCESS TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will provide you with access to the personal information you provided to Ray-Ban.com by allowing you to view, update or correct your information. In order to protect your privacy, we will take steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the private information or enabling you to make corrections. We will accomplish this through the use of passwords and personal data.

If you want to find out what personal information we hold about you, please contact our customer care department at (866) 4RAYBAN (866-472-9226). We may charge you a small fee for providing this information.

## SECURITY

We monitor activity on the website to prevent any unauthorized disclosure of credit card numbers or other personal information. In addition, we utilize a licensed system for credit card authorization and fraud detection. We use industry standard SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption to protect the confidentiality of your personal information.

## UPDATES TO PRIVACY INFORMATION

We reserve the right to make changes to this website, our Privacy Policy, and other policies posted on this website at any time. Please review the website periodically to see any updates to the information provided here. If any of the terms of this Privacy Policy, or other policies posted on this website, shall be deemed invalid, void, or for any reason unenforceable, that term shall be deemed severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any remaining term or condition. This privacy policy was last updated on February 9, 2011.
